Finding Aid for the Al Lewis Scripts PASC.0136
UCLA Library Special Collections
Al Lewis scripts
1943-1954
UCLA Library Special Collections
PASC.0136
5.5 Linear Feet (13 boxes)
Al Lewis was best known as a writer and director for the radio and television series Our Miss Brooks. The collection consists of radio, television, and motion picture scripts related to Lewis's career.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift, 1972.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 999644623606533
Biography
Al Lewis was best known as a writer and director. He began his career as an actor in vaudeville, plays, and motion pictures and was a radio writer for Walter O'Keefe, Milton Berle, and Fred Allen. His numerous credits include the motion pictures Ma and Pa Kettle and Our Miss Brooks and the radio and television series Our Miss Brooks.
Scope and Content
Collection consists primarily of radio scripts related to the career of writer and director Al Lewis. Includes scripts for radio programs such as Our Miss Brooks (June 23, 1948-February 28, 1954), The Danny Kaye Show, G.I. Journal, Mail Call, Sweeney and March, The Philco Radio Times, and Request Performance. Also includes television and motion picture scripts.
Related Material
Lou Derman papers (Collection PASC 99). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, UCLA.
Our Miss Brooks radio and television scripts (Collection PASC 60). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, UCLA.
Radio scripts; Television writers -- Archives.; Radio writers -- United States -- Archives.; Lewis, Al--Archives.
- Comedy materials
  - SKETCHES AND MONOLOGUES
    - (), n.d. (Box 13)
- Motion Pictures
  - MA AND PA KETTLE
    - (), n.d.; First draft. (Box 13)
    - (), n.d.; Revised. first draft. (Box 13)
    - (), n.d.; Revised final, 1948. (Box 13)
- Radio
  - CAMEL PROGRAM (THE)
    - ()., 2/18/1944 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - ()., 7/21/1944; 70 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - ()., 8/4/1944; 72 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - (), n.d.; Sketches (5 items) (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - COMMAND PERFORMANCE
    - ()., 12/16/1944; # 154 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - ()., 12/20/1945; # 203 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - ()., 12/30/1944; # 156 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - ()., 9/30/1944; # 140 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - DANNY KAYE SHOW
    - ()., 11/16/1945 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - ()., 2/10/1945 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - ()., 2/17/1945 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - ()., 2/24/1945 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - ()., 2/3/1945 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - ()., 3/15/1946 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - ()., 3/22/1946 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - ()., 3/29/1946 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - ()., 3/3/1945 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - ()., 3/8/1946 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - ()., 4/12/1946 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - ()., 4/5/1945 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - ()., 4/5/1946 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - ()., 5/10/1946 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - ()., 5/24/1946 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - ()., 5/3/1946 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - ()., 5/31/1946 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - G.I. JOURNAL
    - (), n.d.; 74 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - (), n.d.; 69 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - (), n.d.; 79 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - (), n.d.; 80 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - (), n.d.; 85 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - (), n.d.; 86 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - (), n.d.; 87 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - (), n.d.; 88 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - (), n.d.; 92 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - (), n.d.; 93 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - (), n.d.; 94 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - (), n.d.; 98 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - (), n.d.; # 102 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - (), n.d.; # 103 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - (), n.d.; # 114 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - (), n.d.; # 123 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - JUBILEE
    - ()., 5/8/1944; 79 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - (), n.d.; 92 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - MAIL CALL
    - ()., 1/17/1945; # 127 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - ()., 1/31/1945; # 129 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - ()., 11/3/1943; 63 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - ()., 12/1/1943; 67 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - ()., 2/28/1945; # 134 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - ()., 4/18/1945; # 141 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - ()., 5/2/1944; 89 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - ()., 6/13/1945; # 149 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - ()., 6/21/1944; 97 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - ()., 7/5/1944; 99 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - ()., 8/2/1944; # 103 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - ()., 8/29/1945; # 159 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - (), n.d.; 74 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - ONLY YESTERDAY
    - ()., 3/14/1943 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - ()., 3/21/1943 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - OUR MISS BROOKS
    - ()., 1/1/1950 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - ()., 1/10/1953 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - ()., 1/11/1953 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - ()., 1/13/1952 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - ()., 1/14/1951 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - ()., 1/15/1950 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - ()., 1/2/1949 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - ()., 1/20/1952 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - ()., 1/21/1951 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - ()., 1/22/1950 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - ()., 1/22/1954 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - ()., 1/25/1953 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - ()., 1/27/1952 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - ()., 1/29/1950 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - ()., 1/30/1949 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - ()., 1/6/1949 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - ()., 1/6/1952 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - ()., 1/6/1954 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - ()., 1/7/1951 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - ()., 1/8/1950 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - ()., 1/9/1949 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - ()., 10/1/1950 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - ()., 10/10/1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - ()., 10/12/1952 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - ()., 10/14/1951 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - ()., 10/15/1950 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - ()., 10/17/1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - ()., 10/19/1952 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - ()., 10/19/1953 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - ()., 10/2/1953 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - ()., 10/21/1951 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - ()., 10/22/1950 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - ()., 10/23/1949 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - ()., 10/23/1953 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - ()., 10/26/1952 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - ()., 10/28/1951 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - ()., 10/29/1950 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - ()., 10/3/1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - ()., 10/30/1949 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - ()., 10/30/1953 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - ()., 10/31/1948 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - ()., 10/5/1952 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - ()., 10/7/1951 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - ()., 10/8/1950 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - ()., 10/9/1949 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - ()., 11/11/1951 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - ()., 11/12/1950 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - ()., 11/13/1953 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - ()., 11/14/1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - ()., 11/16/1952 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - ()., 11/18/1951 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - ()., 11/19/1950 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - ()., 11/2/1952 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - ()., 11/21/1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - ()., 11/23/1952 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - ()., 11/25/1951 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - ()., 11/27/1953 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - ()., 11/28/1948 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - ()., 11/4/1951 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - ()., 11/5/1950 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - ()., 11/6/1949 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - ()., 11/6/1953 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - ()., 11/7/1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - ()., 11/9/1952 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - ()., 12/10/1950 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - ()., 12/10/1952 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - ()., 12/11/1949 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - ()., 12/12/1948 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - ()., 12/14/1952 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - ()., 12/16/1951 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - ()., 12/17/1950 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - ()., 12/17/1952 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - ()., 12/18/1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - ()., 12/19/1948 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - ()., 12/2/1951 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - ()., 12/21/1950 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - ()., 12/21/1952 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - ()., 12/23/1951 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - ()., 12/24/1950 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - ()., 12/25/1949 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - ()., 12/26/1948 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - ()., 12/28/1950 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - ()., 12/28/1950 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - ()., 12/3/1950 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - ()., 12/30/1951 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - ()., 12/31/1950 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - ()., 12/4/1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - ()., 12/4/1953 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - ()., 12/5/1948 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - ()., 12/7/1952 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - ()., 12/9/1951 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - ()., 2/10/1952 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - ()., 2/12/1950 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - ()., 2/13/1949 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - ()., 2/15/1953 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - ()., 2/17/1952 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - ()., 2/18/1951 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - ()., 2/19/1950 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - ()., 2/19/1953 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - ()., 2/19/1954 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - ()., 2/20/1949 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - ()., 2/24/1952 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - ()., 2/25/1951 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - ()., 2/26/1950 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - ()., 2/27/1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - ()., 2/3/1952 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - ()., 2/5/1950 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - ()., 2/6/1949 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - ()., 2/8/1953 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - ()., 3/1/1953 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - ()., 3/11/1951 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - ()., 3/12/1950 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - ()., 3/12/1953 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - ()., 3/13/1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - ()., 3/16/1952 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - ()., 3/18/1951 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - ()., 3/2/1952 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - ()., 3/20/1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - ()., 3/22/1953 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - ()., 3/23/1952 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - ()., 3/25/1951 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - ()., 3/26/1950 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - ()., 3/27/1949 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - ()., 3/29/1953 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - ()., 3/30/1952 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - ()., 3/4/1951 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - ()., 3/5/1950 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - ()., 3/6/1949 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - ()., 3/8/1953 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - ()., 3/9/1952 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - ()., 4/1/1951 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - ()., 4/10/1949 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - ()., 4/12/1953 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - ()., 4/13/1952 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - ()., 4/15/1951 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - ()., 4/16/1950 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - ()., 4/17/1949 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - ()., 4/19/1953 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - ()., 4/2/1950 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - ()., 4/22/1951 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - ()., 4/23/1950 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - ()., 4/23/1953 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - ()., 4/24/1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - ()., 4/26/1953 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - ()., 4/27/1952 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - ()., 4/29/1951 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - ()., 4/3/1949 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - ()., 4/30/1950 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - ()., 4/30/1953 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - ()., 4/5/1953 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - ()., 4/6/1952 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - ()., 4/8/1951 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - ()., 4/9/1950 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - ()., 5/1/1949 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - ()., 5/11/1952 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - ()., 5/13/1951 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - ()., 5/14/1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - ()., 5/14/1953 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - ()., 5/15/1949 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - ()., 5/17/1953 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - ()., 5/18/1952 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - ()., 5/20/1951 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - ()., 5/21/1953 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - ()., 5/22/1949 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - ()., 5/24/1951 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - ()., 5/24/1953 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - ()., 5/27/1951 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - ()., 5/29/1949 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - ()., 5/3/1953 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - ()., 5/31/1953 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - ()., 5/4/1952 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - ()., 5/7/1950 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - ()., 5/8/1949 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - ()., 6/1/1952 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - ()., 6/10/1951 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - ()., 6/12/1949 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - ()., 6/15/1952 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - ()., 6/22/1952 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - ()., 6/23/1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - ()., 6/25/1952 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - ()., 6/29/1952 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - ()., 6/5/1949 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - ()., 6/7/1951 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - ()., 6/8/1952 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - ()., 7/10/1949 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - ()., 7/12/1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ()., 7/17/1949 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - ()., 7/24/1949 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - ()., 7/26/1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - ()., 7/3/1949 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - ()., 7/31/1949 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - ()., 8/14/1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - ()., 8/16/1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - ()., 8/19/1949 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - ()., 8/21/1949 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - ()., 8/23/1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - ()., 8/7/1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - ()., 8/9/1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - ()., 9/10/1950 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - ()., 9/11/1949 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - ()., 9/17/1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - ()., 9/18/1949 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - ()., 9/18/1953 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - ()., 9/19/1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - ()., 9/24/1950 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - ()., 9/25/1949 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - ()., 9/25/1953 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - ()., 9/26/1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - ()., 9/3/1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - PHILCO RADIO TIME
    - ()., 1/7/1947; 15 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - ()., 11/12/1946; 7 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - ()., 11/18/1946; 8 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - ()., 11/24/1946; 9 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - ()., 12/23/1946; 14 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - (), n.d.; 1 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - (), n.d.; 2 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - (), n.d.; 3 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - REQUEST PERFORMANCE
    - ()., 10/14/1945; 2 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - ()., 11/25/1945; 8 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - ()., 11/4/1945; 5 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - ()., 12/16/1945; 11 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - ()., 12/2/1945; 9 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - ()., 12/9/1945; 10 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - SWEENEY AND MARCH
    - ()., 1/21/1948 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - ()., 1/28/1948 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - ()., 10/22/1947 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - ()., 11/5/1947 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - ()., 12/10/1947 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - ()., 12/17/1947 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - ()., 12/23/1946 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - ()., 2/24/1947 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - ()., 8/30/1947 (Box Unknown container 250 for instance of ()., Folder 21)
    - (), n.d.; Sketches. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Television
  - CAMEL COMEDY CARAVAN
    - (), n.d.; Sketches (8 items) (Box 13)
  - OUR MISS BROOKS
    - (), n.d.; Undated items (7) (Box 13)
  - VARIETY GIRL
    - (), n.d.; Sketches, 1946 (18) (Box 13)